# Matthew DongKyu Cho

GRADUATE RESEARCHER @ SEOUL NATIONAL UNIVERSITY · RESEARCH SCIENTIST INTERN @ LG AI RESEARCH

💌 kulupapa1127@snu.ac.kr | dongkyu.cho@lgresearch.ai | 🗥 umamicode.github.io | 🖸 github.com/umamicode | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/umamicode



# Personal Profile

A Research Scientist Intern at LG AI Research, Data Intelligence Lab. A recent master's graduate from the Graduate School of Data Science, Seoul National University, advised by Professor Sanghack Lee. My research interests include Causal Representation Learning and Domain Generalization.

## Education

#### **Seoul National University**

Seoul, South Korea

March 2021 - August 2023

Master of Science in Data Science

- · Advised by Professor Sanghack Lee
- Courses: Machine Learning and Deep Learning for Data Science, Big Data and Knowledge Management Systems, Software Platforms for Data Science, Machine Learning for Visual Understanding, Text Analytics and Big Data, Causal Inference for Data Science, Special Topics in Data Science: Meta Learning, Data Science Capstone Project, Dissertation Research, Special Lecture on Data Science

**Seoul National University** Seoul, South Korea

Bachelor of Arts in Information Science and Culture / Western History (Double Major)

March 2014 - February 2021

• Graduated with Distinction (Cum Laude)

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**LG AI Research** Seoul, South Korea

Research Scientist Intern July 2023 - Present

- Time-Series Foundation Models, Out-of-distribution generalization
- · Causality-Driven Prediction & Optimization for Decision-Making

#### **Causality Lab, Seoul National University**

Seoul, South Korea

Graduate Research Assistant

July 2021 - Present

• Collaborative Research Projects with corporate partners (NH Investments & LG AI Research)

### **VAIV Company (Former DaumSoft)**

Seoul, South Korea

Analyst Intern

Jan 2019 - Feb 2019

• Data-Driven Market Analysis for corporate clients.

#### **Republic of Korea Armed Forces**

Icheon, South Korea

Military Interpreter

March 2016 - December 2017

- Military Interpreter for the Republic of Korea Armed Forces.
- Technical Skills: Korean-English Interpretation

#### Research

## Learning to ignore: Single Source Domain Generalization via Oracle Regularization

SNU Causality Lab

Causal Representation Learning Workshop at NeurIPS 2023

2023

• Keywords: Causal Representation Learning, Domain Generalization

## Surgical Weight Averaging for Out-of-domain Generalization (Working Title)

**DELPHI: Leveraging Self Knowledge as Teachers for Out-of-domain Robustness** 

LG AI Research

2023

**Working Paper** 

· Keywords: Ensemble Learning, Domain Generalization

#### SNU Causality Lab

**Working Paper** 

• Keywords: Causal Representation Learning, Domain Generalization, Continual Learning

OCTOBER 29, 2023

**Projects** 

#### Stock Interrelation Research using Keyword and Supply Chain data

Seoul, South Korea

Seoul National University and NH Investment & Securities

July 2021 - August 2022

- A collaborative research with NH Investment & Securities.
- A learning pipeline for a Financial Language Model
- Interactive Graph Database using the Bloomberg Supply Chain Data.
- Technical Skills: Financial-Domain specific Language Models, Financial Data, Graph Database.

#### **Towards Language Models Capable of Causal Reasoning**

Seoul, South Korea

Seoul National University and LG AI Research

August 2022 - Present

- Collaborative research with LG AI Research & UNIST
- A Causal NLP Project Under Progress
- Technical Skills: Causal Inference, Large-scale Language Models.

Class Projects Seoul, South Korea

Seoul National University

• Class Project for Special Topics in Data Science- Meta Learning: "Semi-Supervised Federated Learning with Representations"

• Class Project for Machine Learning for Visual Understanding: "A combination approach for wikipedia Image/Caption Matching Competition"

# **Skills**

**Programming** Python, R, SQL.

Miscellaneous Linux, Docker, Neo4j, MFX(Overleaf/R Markdown), Tableau, Git.

**Soft Skills** French, Korean, English-Korean Interpretation

# Languages

**English** Professional proficiency/ TOEFL 118 (2020.08), 116 (2022.08)

**Korean** Native proficiency

**French** Intermediate proficiency/ DELF B1

OCTOBER 29, 2023